Welcome to our training on how to set ASIN specific handling times.
In this video, we'll show you how to set specific handling times for ASINs that may need special
attention or require different preparations than the rest of your catalog.
Doing so can help you manage your order processing pipeline and protect your account health.
Every offer in the Amazon store comes with a customer delivery promise.
This tells a customer when they can expect an order to arrive.
Customers don't like to be kept waiting, and having a shorter default handling time might make your
listings more attractive.
At the same time, keeping the customer delivery promise is very important, meaning late packages
can affect your account health.
What if you want to set a one-day default handling time, but some of the ASINs in your catalog are
hard to get out the door in one day?
Setting ASIN specific handling times can be the solution.
ASIN specific handling times set exceptions to your normal processing times.
If you have a product that you can ship out faster than your default time, or one that needs more
time than normal,
you can use an ASIN specific handling time to give your customer an accurate delivery promise.
As an example, if you've set a one-day default handling time, but one particularly delicate product
needs special prep before it gets shipped out,
you could set that ASIN to a two-day handling time while still delivering your other products swiftly.
Because ASIN specific handling times need to be set separately for each ASIN that you want to change,
you'll need to set them from the Manage Inventory screen.
To get there, open the main menu in Seller Central by selecting the button in the upper left corner
with the three horizontal lines.
Go to Inventory, then select Manage Inventory.
Select the checkbox next to the ASIN in your inventory that you want to modify.
Then select the Edit button at the far right end of that row.
Depending on the size of your screen, you may have to scroll to the right to find that button.
On the screen for editing the details for that ASIN, select the Offer tab and then scroll down to
Handling Time.
You can set the handling time here in Business Days.
So if you enter two, it means that you'll have two business days after receiving an order for that
ASIN,
in which to both ship the product and confirm that shipment in Seller Central.
While you'll normally need to set ASIN specific handling times for ASINs one by one,
you can upload a file to set handling times in bulk if you're familiar with the Inventory Loader
tool.
Search for Modify Handling Time in Seller Central to learn more about this option.
Handling Time is a key part of the Customer Delivery Promise and your account health,
so it's important to have an accurate handling time for each product in your catalog.
If you can ship most of your products swiftly, try setting a one-day default handling time,
and then setting a longer ASIN specific handling time for products that require more care.
That can help you offer customers the shortest delivery time possible, while also protecting your
account health.
For even more techniques about offering the best customer delivery promise possible,
check out the other videos in this series.
This concludes our training on how to set ASIN specific handling times.
Thank you, and happy selling in the Amazon Store!